

3 Cranleigh House, Cranleigh Street, London NW1 1NT <u>ecem.ergin.17@ucl.ac.uk</u> / <u>www.ecemergin.com</u> +44.759.7437058 (Cell)

## Professional Summary

Has been working at the intersection of HCI, digital media and architecture. Skilled in designing experiments; comfortable with combining qualitative and quantitative methods to provide triangulated data. Run workshops with a focus on VR and 360 footages including 3D scanning. As well, participated in public engagement projects in the UK and overseas locations.

## Education

The Bartlett School of Architecture, University College London, London, UK PhD in Architectural Space and Computation \_ Present \_ Supervisor: Ava Fatah

Yale University School of Architecture, New Haven, CT, USA Visiting Scholar \_ Spring 2020 \_ Supervisor: Keller Easterling

Pratt Institute, Brooklyn, New York, USA

MS: Architecture, Post-Professional \_ May 2016

Istanbul Technical University, Istanbul, Turkey
Master of Science in Architectural Design \_ May 2014

Politecnico di Milano, Milano, Italy

Erasmus program September 2009-August 2010

Istanbul Technical University, Istanbul, Turkey Bachelor of Architecture \_ August 2012

# Publications

Cultural Bulletin – Summer Issue 2019 / Photographs / Pages 42-45 https://www.culturalbulletin.com/magazine/issueb

DIS June'19 Proceedings of the 2019 on Designing Interactive Systems Conference

San Diego, CA, USA / Full Paper / Pages 1183-1193

Title: Flowing Bodies: Exploring the Micro and Macro Scales of Bodily Interactions with Urban Media Installations

Authors: Andre Afonso; Ecem Ergin; Ava Fatah gen. Schieck

(https://doi.org/10.1145/3322276.3322378)

IEEE Pervasive Computing (Volume: 18, Issue: 1, Jan.-March 2019)

Journal Paper / Pages 72-78

Title: Pervasive Displays Research: What's Next?
Authors: Vito Gentile; Passant Elagroudy; Ecem Ergin

 $(\underline{\text{https://doi.org/10.1109/MPRV.2019.2898538}})$ 

Ecem Ergin Page 1 | 3

MAB November'18 Proceedings of Media Architecture Biennale - Central Academy of Fine Arts,

Beijing / Full Paper / Pages 11-18

Title: Times Square in the Era of Post-Truth Politics

Authors: Ecem Ergin; Ava Fatah gen. Schieck (https://doi.org/10.1145/3284389.3284394)

#### UCL Doctoral School Handbook 2018/19 The Art of Research / Collage

https://www.grad.ucl.ac.uk/codes/DoctoralSchool-Handbook-1819.pdf

### Bartlett Doctoral Review 2018 / Paper and Photograph

https://issuu.com/ucl82/docs/bartlett doctoral review 2018

Full Paper

Title: Welcoming the Orange Collars: Robotic Performances in Everyday City Life

Authors: Ecem Ergin; Andre Afonso; Ava Fatah gen. Schieck

(https://doi.org/10.1145/3205873.3205893)

## Professional Experience

### MA: Historic Urban Environments, The Bartlett School of Architecture, London, UK

Post Graduate Teaching Assistant, September 2019- Present

-Assisting teaching staff as well as students of the master program

### International Night-time Design Initiative, New York, US/ London, UK

Researcher, June 2019- Present

-Curating and creating content, as well as reconsidering the branding.

Purpose Group, London, UK

Photographer, August 2018 – July 2019

-Responsible for documentation of workspaces.

#### Purpose Group, London, UK

Project Manager, August 2018 - July 2019

-Duties included outsourcing necessary drawing jobs, editing graphics, and preparing images for promotional materials.

#### Rhizome Architects, Istanbul, Turkey

Architect, September 2016 - September 2017

-Participated in design decision and presentation materials.

#### PRATT 3D LABS, New York, USA

Printing Assistant, February 2016- May 2016

-Printing 3D models with various 3D printers.

# Scholarships and Grants

- UCL-Yale Exchange Fund- Spring 2020 (Tuition Fee)
- Bartlett Architecture Research fund, February 2020
- Bartlett Architecture Research fund, October 2019
- Bartlett Conference Fund, November 2018
- Bartlett Conference Fund, June 2018
- MS: Architecture Merit-based Scholarship, Pratt Institute, 2015-2016
- Ministry of Education in Turkey, Higher Education in Foreign Countries Scholarship (Second place country-wide from all submissions)

Ecem Ergin Page 2 | 3

# Participations

Research Images Exhibition w/ the work titled "As if Hegel was one of us" UCL, London, April 2019

BREAK//LINE Residency Workshop, The Bartlett, London, February 2018

 $WHIST\ Interactive\ theatre\ and\ VR\ Workshop\ with\ Esteban\ Fourmi\ and\ Aoi\ Nakamura\ The\ Bartlett,\ London,\ November\ 2017$ 

Thinking in Sound, Sam Auinger Workshop with Sanford Kwinter, Pratt Institute, NY, September 2015

European Symposium on Research In Architecture And Urban Design November 2014, Paper title: "Trans-material architecture"

7th International Deleuze Conference/ Models, Machines and Memories, Istanbul, July 2014, Organization Committee

Anavatos: The Invisible City, Anavatos Workshop with University of Bari Chios, Greece, September 2014

 $Raise\ your\ head$ , Datascope Workshop with TU Delft Istanbul, May 2013

 ${\it In~between~layers}, \ {\it City~Walls~Workshop~with~Aristoteles~University}, \\ {\it Thessaloniki,~July~2012}$ 

24 Hour workshop beyond the city Beijing/Istanbul/Turin/Delft/Pennsylvania Istanbul, October 2012

Mapping the Commons of Istanbul video workshop Istanbul, October 2012

Danube Delta Advanced Research Center, July 2012 (ISBN 978-975-561-419-9)

 $New\ Horizons\ in\ Campus\ Design\ [In\ Turkish]\ \_\ June\ 2011\ (ISBN\ 978-975-561-404-5)$  http://kampustasarimindayeniufuklar.blogspot.com.tr/

First Year Works, 2009 (ISBN 978-975-561-349-9)

French Cultural Centre, Group exhibition, Photography, 2007

## Interests

- Photographing the built environment over 15 years, exhibited several times in Istanbul.Selection of works could be found: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/art\_ik\_er">www.instagram.com/art\_ik\_er</a>
- Video editing enthusiast with a focus on video art.
- Have been drawing caricatures, mostly related to architectural issues. Working on a child book with these drawings.
- Motorcycle and bike user participated local tours in Istanbul and elsewhere.
- Co-founder of a creative club at Istanbul Technical University called "Cik-Art".
- Secured 1<sup>st</sup> or 2<sup>nd</sup> place in ten chess tournaments as an individual or a team member.
- Was head of the debate team in high school, won local awards.

Ecem Ergin Page 3 | 3